Sometimes the only way to find yourself... is to
lose yourself in someone else's life.
Tara Road is a drama film directed by Gillies MacKinnon.
A grieving Connecticut mother temporarily switches
houses with a woman in Dublin, Ireland.
Marilyn, played by Andie MacDowell.
Ria, played by Olivia Williams.
Colm, played by Stephen Rea.
Danny, played by Iain Glen.
Andy, played by Jean-Marc Barr.
Bernadette, played by Heike Makatsch.
Tara Road is a 2005 drama film directed by Gillies MacKinnon, based
on the 1998 novel of the same name by Maeve Binchy.
The film stars Olivia Williams, Andie MacDowell, Stephen Rea, and Iain
Glen, and was produced by Noel Pearson and David Collins.
Marilyn and Ria—one American, one Irish—do a two-month house swap,
as both have suffered crises and need a change.
Both gradually becomes part of the other’s community, forming new
friendships and gaining perspective on their own lives.
Tara Road was released in Ireland and the United Kingdom in
2005 and later in the United States in 2007.
It received mixed reviews from critics and had a modest box office
performance, with limited international release and distribution.
The film explores themes of upper class, loss of
loved one, bankrupt, cooking, gigolo.
The tone is emotional.